Marvonn Cole Espina

Innovative educator with more than 13 years of teaching experience



Personal details

Name

Marvonn Cole Espina

Email address

marvonnespina1988@gmail.com

Phone number

0840102344

Address

608 11 Chai Badan District, Lopburi 15130 Thailand

Date of birth

March 21, 1988

Place of birth

Monkayo, Davao del Norte, Philippines

Gender

Male

Nationality

Filipino

Civil status

Single

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/marvonnespina-0b3775236

Youtube Self Introduction

youtube.com/watch? v=hJ3rBGoALcA

Education

Master of Arts in Educational Management Jun 2015 - Apr 2018

Rizal Memorial Colleges, Davao City

Awarded Best in Research

Bachelor of Education major in English Jun 2012 - Apr 2015

NDC Tagum Foundation, Inc., Tagum Graduated with distinction

Diploma in Teacher Education Jun 2010 - Apr 2012

North Davao Colleges, Panabo City

Bachelor of Science in Nursing Jun 2005 - Apr 2009

NDC Tagum Foundation, Inc., Tagum Awarded Cum Laude and graduated in top 2.64% of class.

Employment

High School English Teacher

Jun 2022 - Present

Chaibaddanwittaya School, Lopburi, Thailand

- Establishes and enforces rules for student behavior and procedures for maintaining order
- Prepares classroom materials for class activities
- Adapts teaching methods and instructional materials to meet varying needs and interests of students
- Prepares students for standardized ONET tests set by the Ministry of Education in Thailand

Preschool Teacher

Jun 2020 - Mar 2022

ABC Childcare Christian School, Inc., Tagum, Philippines

- Developed and implemented lesson plans to meet student needs.
- Maintained student progress records with regular updates to students and parents
- Attended educational conferences, trainings, workshops and seminars in preparation for the transition of teaching modalities during the pandemic.
- Conducted teacher-parent conferences to discuss children's school adjustments.

High School Principal & Senior High School Jun 2015 - Mar 2020 English Instructor

NDC Tagum Foundation, Inc., Tagum, Philippines

- Established and enforced rules and procedures for maintaining order in school
- Recommended programs to improve teacher performance
- Mentored and counseled teachers in educational practices and techniques to improve performance
- Adapted teaching methods and instructional materials to meet varying needs of students
- Instructed through lectures and activities

Skills

- Analytical
- Decision-making
- Team Leader/Player
- Problem-solving
- Commitment to excellence
- Interpersonal
- Adaptability
- Time Management
- Organizational
- Collaboration
- Creative Thinking

Hobbies

- Volunteering and community outreach
- Youth leadership
- Photography
- Listening to different genres of music
- Travelling

References

Phoebe Castromayor

ABC Childcare Christian School, Inc., Tagum 09776333411,

phoebecastromayor21@gmail.

Evenie Joy Colegado

Institution of Northern Davao, Inc., Mawab 09776333411, eveniejoy21@gmail.com

Leodemareden Vicente

ABC Childcare Christian School Inc., Tagum 09776333411, vicentemacoy@gmail.com

High School English Teacher

Jun 2012 - Mar 2015

Phayakkaphumwitayyakarn School, Mahasarakam, Thailand

- Established and enforces rules for student behavior and procedures for maintaining order
- Prepared classroom materials for class activities
- Established clear objectives for all lessons and activities
- Adapted teaching methods and instructional materials to meet varying needs and interests of students
- Prepared students for standardized ONET tests set by the Ministry of Education in Thailand

High School English & Health Teacher

Jun 2009 - Mar 2012

Institution of Northern Davao, Inc., Mawab

- Developed and implemented curriculum to meet established learning objectives
- Established clear objectives for all lessons and community health outreach programs
- Developed and implemented school programs for health subjects and activities
- Evaluated health education programs and helped in assessing student health conditions

Languages

English

Tagalog

Thai

Profile

Skilled educator, practical and innovative with solid teaching and management background for more than thirteen years. Interesting, creative and engaging lecturer successful at facilitating discussions and activities. Strong organizational, relationship-building and conflict mediation skills.

Achievements

- Most Dedicated Teacher Awardee, ABCCCSI, 2021
- Best in Research in Graduate Studies, RMC, 2018
- Outstanding School Principal, 2018
- Oratorical Speech & Story Telling Grand Slam Coach, 2015-
- 2020 Outstanding CVEG Scholar & Student Leader, NDC TFI,
- 2010 Cum Laude, BS Nursing, 2009

Certificates

PRC License in Teaching

PRC License in Nursing

TESOL